You know, the consumer type of firework can be a lot of fun to any holiday or party event.
Hi, I'm Captain Joe Bruni with over three decades of firefighting and emergency medical service experience.
The one type of consumer firework, that seems to be the most common in the United States, is the sparkler.
Sparklers are found across the United States during holiday and party events.
When sparklers are used, they can reach eleven hundred to eighteen hundred degrees, that's a very hot item.
So, ensure any time sparklers are used that they are used somewhere in an open area, closely supervised by an adult, and kept away from any flammable or combustible product.
Things such as leaves, dried grass also can create a problem even in the open area, with the sparklers, shower of sparks, and heat.
So, remember anytime sparklers are being used, use them in an open, wide area far away from any type of combustible, or flammable product.
It may also be a good idea to keep some type of bucket of water, or fire extinguisher handy, just in case there's a problem related to fire.
I'm Captain Joe Bruni, stay safe and we'll see you next time.